A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Housing Interests, Series J FA319
Rockefeller Archive Center
- New York State and New York City Housing
  - New York City Housing Authority, 1942-1955 (Box 17, Folder 153)
    David Rockefeller declined invitation to become member. Correspondents include David Rockefeller.
    179.7A
  - New York City Housing Authority, 1954-1955 (Box 17, Folder 0153A)
  - New York State Committee on Discrimination in Housing (SCAD), 1949-1961 (Box 23, Folder 213)
    No family interest or participation. Correspondents include W. T. Lindquist.
    179.23
- Chicago Housing Project
  - Chicago Housing Project, 1925-1942 (Box 17, Folder 154)
    Exchange of information between office and Marshall Field. Information and data; retaining of Thomas; project progress; A. J. Parkin as manager. Correspondents include Arthur woods, Marshall Field, Kenneth Chorley, G. Richardson, Charles O. Heydt, Frank Staley, A. J. Thomas.
    179.8
- Michigan Boulevard Garden Apartments
  - Michigan Boulevard Garden Apartments, 1927-1936 (Box 17, Folder 155)
    Exchange of information; rent reductions. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, R. C. Bruce, A. D. Taylor, A. J. Thomas.
    179.8A
- Van Tassel Apartments
  - Van Tassel Apartments, 1928-1938 (Box 17, Folder 156)
    Selection of site and name; title, plans, construction. Transfer from Empire Mortgage Company to Van Tassel, Inc. Formal opening; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s acquisition of Van Tassel Apartments; revised rates; renting problems. Dissolution of Van Tassel Apartments, Inc. War measures. Possible sale to C. T. Chambers; Harry S. Jensen's policies; administrative details. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Frank Staley, Harry S. Jensen, James F. Brannigan, Phillip Keebler, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., A. J. Thomas.
    179.9
  - Van Tassel Apartments, 1938-1955 (Box 17, Folder 157)
  - Van Tassel Apartments - Harry S. Jensen, 1929-1959 (Box 17, Folder 158)
  - Van Tassel Apartments - Photographs, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 159)
  - Van Tassel Apartments - Mortgage and Bonds, 1933-1940 (Box 17, Folder 160)
    Mortgage and bonds from Van Tassel Apartments to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Van Tassel Apartments - Booklets (Box 17, Folder 161)
  - Van Tassel Apartments - Foreclosure of Mortgage, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 162)
    Recording mortgage; foreclosure; purchase at sale.
    179.92
  - Van Tassel Apartments - Deed from Referee to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1933 (Box 18, Folder 163)
  - Van Tassel Apartments - Taxes - Reduction in Assessments, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 164)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s efforts to reduce assessment were successful.
    179.95
  - Van Tassel Apartments - Publicity, 1928-1929 (Box 18, Folder 165)
    Advertising, publicity, clippings. Correspondents include Frank Staley, Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., H. S. Jensen.
    179.97
  - Van Tassel Apartments - Publicity, 1928-1930 (Box 18, Folder 166)
  - Van Tassel Apartments - Finances, 1929-1930 (Box 18, Folder 167)
    Arrangements for financing Apartments; foreclosure; dissolution.
    179.98
  - Van Tassel Apartments - Stock, 1930 (Box 18, Folder 168)
    1/13/31 payment of $133,548.08.
  - Van Tassel Apartments - Garage, 1929-1935 (Box 18, Folder 169)
    Plans; payments to construction fund. Administrative details; rent. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler, H. S. Jensen, Frank Staley, A. J. Thomas, Charles O. Heydt.
    179.910
  - Financial Statements, 1932-1942 (Box 18, Folder 170)
    179.913
  - Van Tassel Apartments - Conveyance to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1941 (Box 18, Folder 171)
    Conveyance from Empire Mortgage Company to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. of garage and playground property. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler.
    179.915
  - Van Tassel Apartments - Sale, 1942-1954 (Box 18, Folder 172)
    Offers; sale to C. T. Chambers; Chamber's sale. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, Phillip Keebler, A. LeRoy Chipman, Frank Staley.
    179.916
- Brooklyn Model Garden Apartments
  - Brooklyn Model Garden Apartments, 1927-1944 (Box 19, Folder 173)
    Prospectus; photographs; history of the project. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. underwrote portion of stock; consented to mortgage; sold his interest. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, Bertram Cutler, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., A. LeRoy Chipman.
    179.10
- Housing Projects and Associations
  - Suggested Colored Housing Projects, 1925-1941 (Box 19, Folder 174)
    Appeals and proposals. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
    179.11
  - Architects Small House Service Bureau, 1929-1933 (Box 19, Folder 175)
    1930 and 1932 pledges; declinations of other appeals. Correspondents include Thomas B. Appleget, Kenneth Chorley, Arthur W. Packard.
    179.12
  - National Housing Association, 1917-1931 (Box 19, Folder 176)
    Appeals; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. donation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt.
    179.13
  - Institute for Economic Research, 1932-1938 (Box 19, Folder 177)
    Organization of institute; appeals. Nelson A. Rockefeller contribution to Dr. Ely for his personal use. Correspondents include Dr. Richard T. Ely, Charles O. Heydt, Arthur W. Packard, Kenneth Chorley.
    179.14
- Citizens Housing and Planning Council, Inc.
  - Citizens Housing and Planning Council, Inc., 1937-1949 (Box 19, Folder 178)
    Plans and policies; David Rockefeller and Nelson A. Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Nelson A. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Charles O. Heydt, W. T. Lindquist.
    179.16
  - Citizens Housing and Planning Council, Inc., 1937-1949 (Box 19, Folder 0178A)
  - Citizens Housing and Planning Council, Inc., 1956-1962 (Box 19, Folder 179)
  - Citizens Housing and Planning Council, Inc., 1956-1962 (Box 19, Folder 0179A)
  - Citizens Housing and Planning Council, Inc., 1952-1961 (Box 19, Folder 180)
  - Citizens Housing and Planning Council, Inc., 1952-1961 (Box 19, Folder 0180A)
  - Citizens Housing and Planning Council, Inc. - Printed Material, 1947-1965 (Box 19, Folder 181)
- Tarrytown Housing
  - PHC Corporation, 1941-1953 (Box 20, Folder 182)
    Mass-produced housing; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. had two pre-fabricated houses built in Tarrytown. Corporation attempted to get grant from Rockefeller Foundation or guaranteed load from Chase Bank - failed. Plans investigated by Raymond B. Fosdick. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., E. W. Paney, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    179.17
  - Tarrytown Housing, 1947-1954 (Box 20, Folder 185)
    179.21
- National Committee on Housing Emergency
  - National Committee on Housing Emergency, 1941-1948 (Box 20, Folder 183)
    Appeals. Dissolution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.
    179.18
  - National Committee on Housing Emergency, 1941-1948 (Box 20, Folder 0183A)
    David Rockefeller's annual dues.
- Pre-Fabricated Housing
  - Pre-Fabricated Housing, 1940-1948 (Box 20, Folder 184)
    Appeals; Pre-Built Housing Corporation inquiry. Laurance S. Rockefeller interest in aluminum pre-fabrication (McDonnel Aircraft Co.) and steel fabrication (Harman Homes); Laurance S. Rockefeller financed study by J. C. Rogers, Jr. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    179.20
- Morningside Heights
  - Morningside Heights, Inc., 1949-1959 (Box 20, Folder 186)
    Initial plans and organization; suggestions for church center on Heights. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. interest in program; tax exemption; plans for development. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., David Rockefeller, W. T. Lindquist.
    179.22
  - Morningside Heights, Inc., 1947-1961 (Box 20, Folder 0186A)
  - Morningside Heights, Inc., 1947-1961 (Box 20, Folder 187)
    Open per DHS, 2-25-2000.
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - Housing for Church Center Employees, 1954-1956 (Box 20, Folder 188)
    Building plans of Morningside apartments for Council employees. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, W. T. Lindquist.
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - David Rockefeller, 1946-1947 (Box 20, Folder 189)
    David Rockefeller's initial interest in redevelopment of Morningside area; preliminary studies. Drafts of policy statements. David Rockefeller president of Morningside Heights, Inc. Participation of other institutions; organization of Remedco; problems. Rockefeller Brothers Fund contribution toward surveys. General Grant and Morningside Gardens Apartments. Membership changes. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard, L. M. Orton, W. T. Lindquist, Grayson Kirk.
    179.22D
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - David Rockefeller, 1947-1948 (Box 20, Folder 190)
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - David Rockefeller, 1948-1949 (Box 21, Folder 191)
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - David Rockefeller, 1948-1950 (Box 21, Folder 192)
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - David Rockefeller, 1951-1952 (Box 21, Folder 193)
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - David Rockefeller, 1951-1955 (Box 21, Folder 194)
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - David Rockefeller, 1954-1956 (Box 21, Folder 195)
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - David Rockefeller, 1955-1957 (Box 21, Folder 196)
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - David Rockefeller, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 197)
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - David Rockefeller, 1958-1959 (Box 21, Folder 198)
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - David Rockefeller, 1955-1961 (Box 22, Folder 199)
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - Certificate of Incorporation, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 200)
    Certificate and by-laws.
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - Community Research Associates, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 201)
    Study of conditions and needs.
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - Community Research Associates, 1956-1957 (Box 22, Folder 202)
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - David Rockefeller Interests, 1951-1958 (Box 22, Folder 203)
    David Rockefeller contributions to special projects.
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - Financial Statements, 1947-1961 (Box 22, Folder 204)
    Morningside Heights, Inc. year-end audits.
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - Publicity, 1950-1960 (Box 22, Folder 205)
    Newspaper comments on Morningside Heights development.
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - Remedco, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 206)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. underwrote investment of Morningside institutions in real estate holding corporation, up to $100,000. Remedco to keep up and repair deteriorating housing. Company policies; purchasing program. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., W. T. Lindquist.
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - Remedco, 1949-1961 (Box 23, Folder 207)
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - Cooperative Housing, 1948-1951 (Box 23, Folder 208)
    Plans for development; conflict with Robert Moses; difficulties with residents of the area. Cost problems; 1953 land purchase; 1957 occupancy. Correspondents include W. T. Lindquist, L. M. Orton, David Rockefeller, Robert Moses.
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - Cooperative Housing, 1951-1953 (Box 23, Folder 209)
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - Cooperative Housing, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 210)
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - Cooperative Housing, 1954-1961 (Box 23, Folder 211)
  - Morningside Heights, Inc. - Cooperative Housing - Bylaws, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 212)
  - "Morningside Heights Core Area Study", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 228)
    Includes photographs and maps of Morningside Heights.
- Baptist Home Property
  - Baptist Home Property, 1924-1931 (Box 24, Folder 214)
    City's arrangement with Home; city's sale to Home. Plans for building; transfer of property from Home to Empire Mortgage Company. Correspondents include Raymond B. Fosdick, Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, A. J. Thomas.
    220
- Lavoisier Apartments
  - Lavoisier Apartments, 1929-1941 (Box 24, Folder 215)
    Decision to build; choosing of name; construction; renting. New York Chapter of American Institute of Architects award to Apartments. Upkeep; labor relations; transfer of apartments to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., then to Lawida Corporation. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, A. J. Thomas, Thomas M. Debevoise, Douglas Gibbons.
  - Lavoisier Apartments - Balance Sheets, 1932-1935 (Box 24, Folder 216)
    Profit and loss statements, 1932-1935; balance sheets, 1932-1934; statistical data statements for 1932. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler.
  - Lavoisier Apartments - Leases - Applications, 1931-1947 (Box 24, Folder 217)
    Collections; arrears; complaints; renewals. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt.
    220.1
  - Lavoisier Apartments - Incorporation - Deed, 1930-1935 (Box 24, Folder 218)
    Copies of important papers, including Empire Mortgage Company deed to Lavoisier Apartments. Liquidation. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Charles O. Heydt, Phillip Keebler.
    220.2
  - Lavoisier Apartments - Publicity - Clippings, 1930 (Box 24, Folder 219)
    Releases and newspaper articles. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, A. J. Thomas, Ivy Lee.
    220.5
- Trailer Camp Project
  - Trailer Camp Project, 1937-1939 (Box 24, Folder 220)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller and Nelson A. Rockefeller investigate investment possibilities of a Florida trailer camp. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    79